A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Management Services, Office Files of Steven Lawry FA652
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Management Services, Office Files of Steven Lawry
1994-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lawry, Steven W.
Ford Foundation
FA652
0.76 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 1 series:
1. Program Assistants/Associates Program Files.
Biographical / Historical
Steven Lawry is a social scientist whose career has focused on natural resources, forest management, and land rights. For a period spanning more than ten years, he worked at the Ford Foundation. He started at the Foundation as an Assistant Representative and Program Officer in the Africa and Middle East, South Africa and Namibia Program where he was based in Windhoek, Namibia. Then he moved to the Africa and Middle East, Middle East and North Africa Program where he served as the Foundation's Representative in Cairo, Egypt. He was later appointed Director of the Office of Management Services. While in that position, he briefly served as Acting Representative for the India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka Program.
After he left the Ford Foundation, Lawry served for a couple of years as the President of Antioch College from 2006 to 2007. He then became a Senior Research Fellow at the Harvard Kennedy School. In 2014, he joined the Center for International Forestry Research (CIFOR) as a Principal Scientist and became a Senior Associate in 2019.
Lawry earned a B.A. in government and international relations from Florida State University in 1973, a master's degree in urban and regional planning from Florida State University in 1975, and a Ph.D. in land resources from the Nelson Institute for Environmental Studies at the University of Wisconsin-Madison in 1988.
Scope and Contents
Contains documentation of meetings, orientation, surveys, reviews, etc.
- Program Assistants/Associates Program Files, 1994-2003; I
  - Program Assistants, 1994-1996 -- FAP, Expenses (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1994-1996 -- PA Background, Diversity Information (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1994-1996 -- Orientation (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1994-1996 -- PA Meetings, Workshops, Interviews (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1996-1998 -- FAP, Budget, Expenses, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1996-1998 -- Orientation (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants, 1996-1998 -- Recruitment, Application Forms, 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants -- Survey, Results, 1996 July (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants -- Miscellaneous Files, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Program Assistants -- Retreat, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Program Assistants -- FAPs, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Program Assistants, 1998-2000 -- Guidelines, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Program Associates -- Interviews, Evaluations (folder 1), 2002 (Box 2)
  - Program Associates -- Interviews, Evaluations (folder 2), 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Program Associates Program Review -- Steering Committee Meeting, 2002 April 16 (Box 2)
  - Program Associates, 1998-2001 (Box 2)
  - Program Associates -- Program Review Summary and Recommendations, Orientation Notebook, Directory, 2000-2003 (Box 2)